Devdutt Jadeja

Email: devduttjadeja01@gmail.com

Phone: +1(438)-357-9977

LinkedIn:www.linkedin.com/in/devdutt-jadeja-572865b8/

Github:https://github.com/devduttjadeja

PROFILE SUMMARY

Software professional graduated from Concordia University in April 2021 with 5+ years of industry experience in Java, Angular, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Restful API and Database(Oracle, DB2, MongoDB). Worked across different domains such as Financial Services, Insurance and Telecom. Looking for a full time opportunity as a Software Developer.

SKILLS

Programming: Java 8+, Python, Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Hibernate, SQL

Restful API, Web-services (SOAP and Rest)

UI Framework: Angular 4+, Vaadin

Automation: Selenium

Machine Learning: scikit-learn, NumPy, matplotlib

Tools: Eclipse, IntelliJ, PyCharm, STS, PLSQL Developer

Code Quality: SonarQube Server and SonarLint Databases: Oracle 11G, DB2, MongoDB, H2
Testing Framework: Junit, Power Mock, Mockito

Build Tools CI/CD: Maven, Jenkins

Defect Tracking Tool: ALM (HP QC), Jira, Rally, Redmine

Version Control Tools: SVN, GIT

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Antea AIM

Montreal, Canada August 2020 – April 2021

· Responsibilities:

Software Developer

- · Working on the product created by Antea for managing assets of Oil & Gas industry while following the standards of American Petroleum Institute (API).
- · Implementing all the new features on Vaadin for developing UI and using Java, Spring Boot, JPA, Hibernate, PL/SQl, H2 for backend development.
- · Solving bugs for the new release
- · Maintaining code quality using tools like SonarQube Server and SonarLint.
- · Perform unit testing (Junit Jmockit).

Accenture Solutions Pvt Ltd.

Pune, India

Application Development Senior Analyst

July 2015 - Feb 2019

Domain: InsuranceResponsibilities:

- · Worked on Allianz France web application module and Developed end to end products which includes requirement gathering, code development, unit testing, release management and maintenance.
- · Used Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, DB2, JPA, Angular4+, HTML, CSS, Javascript.
- · Implementing all the new functionalities and modification as per request made by the client.
- · Implemented test suites to assess software functionality and performance.

- · Analyze the Detailed Function Design (DFD) to understand the requirement.
- · Technical Implementation of the Functional Design and handle defects.
- · Maintaining code quality using tools like SonarQube Server and SonarLint.
- · Perform unit testing (Junit Jmockit).

Tata Consultancy Services Limited

System Engineer

Pune, India *July 2013 – July 2015*

Domain: TelecomResponsibilities:

- · Expertise in Vodafone CPOS web application module and end-to-end Development of software products.
- · Used Core Java, Spring MVC, Hibenate, Angular 2, HTML, CSS, Javascript.
- · Development of fresh requirements and enhancements of existing features.
- · Making changes in GUI.

EDUCATION

Concordia University

Montreal, Canada

Master's of Applied Computer Science

Sep 2019 - Apr 2021

Coursework:

Advanced Programming Practice, Distributed System Design, Algorithm Design Techniques, Machine Learning, Introduction To A.I, Comparative Study of Programming Language, Intelligent Systems.

GPA: 3.95/4.3

M.S University

Vadodara, India

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science

Jun 2009 - Apr2013

GPA: 3.78/4.0

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Risk Game (Java)

Advanced Programming Practice

- · Developed Risk game as per the rule of the game and build requirement.
- · Implemented various Java design patterns namely, Singleton, Observer, Adapter, Strategy, Builder pattern.
- · Game development involved the use of Maven project, Javadoc, Github, Junit, refactoring, and followed MVC architecture.